1. When a consumer finds that an item she or he bought is faulty or in some other way does not live up to the manufacturer's claim for it, the first step is to present the warranty (保单), or any other records which might help, at the store of purchase. (CET-4 1993.6, Passage 3, Paragraph 1)

当顾客发现他们购买的商品有问题或者跟厂家的宣传不一样时，首先要做的就是向商店出示保证书或者其他记录。　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　
2. It may have been a sharp criticism of the pupil's technical abilities in writing, but it was also a sad reflection on the teacher who had omitted to read the essay, which contained some beautiful expressions of the child's deep feelings. (CET-4 1991.6, Passage 1, Paragraph 3)

这是对孩子写作能力的尖刻批判，但是它也反映了老师没有仔细阅读作文的内容，而这作文中包含了一些美丽的句子，表达了孩子们内心深刻的情感。　　　　　　　　　
3. In the past our own blocks of flats have been associated with the lower-income groups and they have lacked the obvious provisions, such as central heating, constant hot water supply, electrically operated lifts from top to bottom, and so on, as well as such details important notwithstanding (然而), as easy facilities for disposal of dust and rubbish and storage places for baby carriages on the ground floor, playgrounds for children on the top of the buildings, and drying grounds for washing. (CET-4, 1995.6, Passage 3, Paragraph 1)

在过去，高层公寓一直和低收入人群联系在一起，并且这些公寓缺少最起码的生活设施，比如集中供暖系统、24小时热水、直达电梯等等，以及其它尽管微不足道但是很重要的生活设施，诸如能方便处理垃圾的设施、一楼存放婴儿车的空间、楼顶的儿童游戏场地以及晾晒衣服的空地等。

4. However, children and teens with a cold or flu should not take aspirin for pain relief because of the risk of Reye syndrome（综合症）, a rare but serious condition of the liver and central nervous system. (CET-4 2005.1, Passage 1, Paragraph 7)

不过，患感冒和流感的小孩和青年不要为了减轻病痛而服用阿司匹林，他们有得Reye综合症的危险，Reye综合症是一种极为少见却很严重的肝和中枢神经系统疾病。　

5. Believe it or not, optical illusion can cut highway crashes. (CET-4 2000.1, Passage 2, Paragraph 1)

不论你相信与否，视觉上的错觉能被用来减少高速公路上的车祸。

6. What is remarkable about the history of toys is not so much how they changed over the centuries but how much they have remained the same.（CET-4 1999.6, Passage 4, Paragraph 3）

研究玩具的历史，我们会发现引人注目的不是它们随时间的变化而变化，而是它们随时间的变化而保持不变。(What is remarkable about sth is not so much A, but B这个句型对于写社会问题类作文是个极好的句型，请背诵仿写这句话50遍以上。) 

7. But the careful use of small monetary rewards sparks creativity in grade-school children, suggesting that properly presented inducements (刺激) indeed aid inventiveness, according to a study in the June Journal of Personality and Social Psychology. (CET-4 1997.1, Passage 4, Paragraph 2)

但是慎重地使用少量的金钱奖励能激发小学生的创造力，这一点证明合理的刺激确实对创造力有帮助，这是《个性与社会心理学》杂志六月刊的研究结果。

8. “Résumés (简历) arrive with stains. Some candidates don't bother to spell the company’s name correctly. Once I see a mistake, I eliminate the candidate,” Crossley concludes. (CET-4 1995.6, Passage 2, Paragraph 2)

Crossley总结说，“有的简历上有墨水污迹，有的申请人把公司的名字都写错了，一旦发现这样的错误，我立刻取消申请人的资格。”

9. But in actual practice this system breaks down in many ways, because the organism and the environment are constantly interacting so that the environment is modified by the organism and vice versa(反之亦然). (CET-4 1996.1 Passage 3, paragraph 1)

但是，在实际操作中，这种体系说法就不太容易行得通了，因为，环境和有机体通常是互动的，环境被有机体影响，而反过来有机体也是被环境所影响的。

10. Or every social situation, there is a permissible time that you can hold a person's gaze without being intimate, rude, or aggressive. (CET-4 1996.6, Passage 1, Paragraph 1)

对各种社交场合来说,在一段允许的时间内你可以与人对视,而不显得亲密、粗鲁或咄咄逼人

11. here is no such a thing as teaching someone how to use a computer. One can only teach peple to use this or that program and generally that is easily accomplished. (CET-4 1998.6 Passage 2, paragraph 4)

我们不能说教人学会使用计算机，我们只能说学会使用这一套或是那一套软件，这点是很容易的。

12. The fine points of etiquette (礼节) that children might once have learned at the table by observation or instruction from parents and grandparents (“Chew with your mouth closed.” “Keep your elbows off the table.”) must be picked up elsewhere.（CET-4, 2003.12 Passage 3, paragraph 6）

本来孩子们可以在餐桌上通过观察或者由父母，祖父母指导而学会的礼节中的细节（“要闭上嘴巴咀嚼食物”，“肘部不要碰到餐桌”等）必须在其他场合去学习了。

13. More important, perhaps, education teaches us to see the connections between things, as well as to see beyond our immediate needs. (CET-4 2002.12, Passage 2, Paragraph 5)

更重要的也许是，教育教我们去发现事物之间的联系，同时去挖掘超越我们眼前需要的东西

14. It’s also true of children who suffer for years in foster homes（收养孩子的家庭）because of parents who can’t or won’t care for them but refuse to give up custody（监护）rights (CET-4 2003.6, Passage 4, Paragraph 1)

同时，对那些由于父母没有能力或不愿意照顾他们，但又不肯放弃监护权而痛苦地生活在收养家庭的孩子来说也是如此。　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　
15. If they are not sincere and do not practise what they preach(说教), their children may grow confused and emotionally insecure when they grow old enough to think for themselves, and realize they have been to some extent fooled. (CET-4 1998.1, Passage 1, Paragraph 3)

如果他们对于自己说教的东西不真诚对待也不去执行的话，孩子们就会不知所措，而且从情感上来说会有不安全感。当他们成长到能够自己思考问题的时候，就会感觉到自己从某种程度上说被欺骗了。

16. In fact, the analysis showed, normal children ages 9 to 17 exhibit a higher level of anxiety today than children who were treated for mental illness 50 years ago. (CET-4 2003.12, Passage 1, Paragraph 1)

据报告分析，事实上，当今正常的9至17岁之间的儿童比五十年前接受精神疾病治疗的儿童表现更高程度的焦虑。

17. Coffman and district officials last week agreed on a state emergency plan freeing up a $ 9.8 million loan that enabled the payroll(工资单)to be met for 2,700 teachers and staff in time for the holidays. (CET-4 2005.12, Passage 2, Paragraph 4)

上个星期，科夫曼以及区政府官员就一项州应急计划达成了一致，该计划将由州政府提供980万美元的贷款，用于在假期到来之前支付2700名教职工的薪水。

18. The speaker, a teacher from a community college, addressed a sympathetic audience. (CET-4 1996.1, Passage 4, Paragraph 1)

社区大学的一位老师所发表的讲话得到了听众的支持。

19. Nor did the lapses appear to be entirely random (随机的). (CET-4 2003.6, Passage 3, Paragraph 1)

这些差错并不是毫无规律的。

20. Medical Center of overweight police officers and other public employees confirmed that those who dieted without exercise regained almost all their old weight, while those who worked exercise into their daily routine maintained their new weight.（CET-4, 2005.1 Passage 4, paragraph 3）

波士顿大学医疗中心通过对超重的警官和其他公职人员的研究证实，那些只节食不锻炼的人体重几乎都会恢复原样，而那些将锻炼纳入日常作息生活的人却能保持新的体重。

21. Graduated licensing systems have reduced teenage driver crashes, according to recent studies, about half of the states now have some sort of graduated licensing system in place, but only 10 of those states have restrictions on passengers, California is the strictest, with a novice driver prohibited from carrying any passenger under 20 (without the presence of an adult over 25) for the first six months. (CET-4 2003.9 Passage 1, Paragraph 5)

根据最近的研究，渐进式制度已经降低了十几岁少年驾车的事故。大约有一半的州建立了某种渐进式驾照制度，但是只有十个州对载客有限制。加利福尼亚州最严格，规定新司机在最初六个月内不准搭载二十岁以下乘客(除非有一个25岁以上的成年人在场)。

（注：上下文中Graduated licensing systems指代 “新的颁发驾照体系”，这里引申翻译为“渐进式制度”）

22. Its strategy rests on two beliefs: first, a global product offers economies of scale with which local brands cannot compete, and second, consumers in the 21st century are drawn to “global” as a concept, “Global” does not mean products that are consciously identified as American, but ones that consumers—especially young people—see as part of a modern, innovative (创新的) world in which people are linked across cultures by shared beliefs and tastes. (CET-4 2005.12, Passage 1, Paragraph 3)

这家公司的营销策略基于以下两个理念。其一，一种全球性的产品提供的规模经济是任何地区品牌都无法竞争的；其二，21世纪的消费者都认可“全球化”不是指人们意识中认可的美国产品，而是指导那些被消费者特别是年轻人视为现代、创新世界特征的东西。在这个世界中，相同的信仰和相同的口味把不同文化背景的人们联系在一起。

(注：本句第二点的主干为：“Global” does not mean products that …, but ones that … in which…，其中ones指代products。TNND,四级也很变态啊,这句话竟然5行！别小瞧它啊！如果想在写作中写出类似这么牛的句子，请把这句话狂念100遍！J）

23. And in general, flu symptoms including fever and chills, sore throat and body aches come on suddenly and are more severe than cold symptoms. (CET-4 2005.1 Passage 1, Paragraph 5)

而且一般来说，流感的症状包括发烧和发冷、嗓子疼和深身酸痛，比普通感冒的症状来得突然和猛烈。

24. Consumers are being confused and misled by the hodge-podge (大杂烩) of environmental claims made by household products, according to a “green labeling” study published by Consumers International Friday . (CET-4 2005.6, Passage 3, Paragraph 1)

根据本周五国际消费者联盟公布的一份“绿色环保标志”调研报告，家用商品上形形色色的绿色环保说明使消费者感到困惑，并被误导。

25. If you say to your children “I’m sorry I got angry with you, but…”, what follows that “but” can render the apology ineffective : “I had a bad day” or “Your noise was giving me a headache” leaves the person who has been injured feeling that he should be apologizing for his bad behavior in expecting an apology. (CET-4 2005.12, Passage 4, Paragraph 2)

如果你对孩子说：“对不起我对你发火了，但是……”，“但是”后面的话可能使得这个道歉毫无意义。但是后面的“我今天情绪不好”，或者“你发出的噪声使我头疼”，这类的话使受到伤害的人感到不是你在向他道歉，而是他应该(为他的不当行为)向你道歉。

26. So you cut off eye contact, what sociologist Erving Goffman (1963) calls “a dimming of the lights.” (CET-4, 1996.6, Passage 1, Paragraph 1)

因此你停止跟别人的目光交流，社会学家欧文•戈夫曼在1963年把这叫做“黯淡的眼神”。

（注：这里light表示眼神。“黯淡的眼神”这个表达来自美国社会人类学家欧文•戈夫曼(Erving Goffman)的名著《公众场合下的行为》（1963年）；Erving Goffman: Behavior in Public Places, New York: Free Press, 1963. 本书阐述了在人际交往的场合中，行为者选择适当的表情、动作或语言以使知觉者对自己产生某种特定的看法。）

27. While it’s true that we all need a career, it is equally true that our civilization has accumulated an incredible amount of knowledge in fields far removed from our own and that we are better for our understanding of these other contributions─be they scientific or artistic. (CET-4, 2002.12, Passage 2, Paragraph 5)

诚然，我们都需要一个职业，但同时我们也应该看到文明已经在一些远离我们自身职业的领域积聚了大量的知识，由于理解了这些文明的贡献——不管它们是科学还是艺术的，我们的生活将更加美好。

(注：本句主干为：it is equally true that ......and that......；it却是形式主语，真正主语是that从句，that从句太长，所以用it指代；far removed from our own过去分词短语做fields的定语；破折号后面的部分是补充说明other contributions。嘿嘿，很爽的感觉啊,别小瞧四级啊！如果想在写作中写出类似这么牛的句子，请把这句话狂念100遍！J）

28. Tracking whales is but one example of an exciting new world just opening to civilian scientists after the cold war as the Navy starts to share and partly uncover its global network of underwater listening system built over the decades to track the ships of potential enemies. (CET-4 2002.6, Passage 3, Paragraph 3)

冷战结束后，海军对几十年来为跟踪潜在敌舰而建立的全球海底监听系统作了部分解密，并开始同他人分享。追踪蓝鲸只不过是令人激动的新世界向民用科学家开放的一个例子。

29. While any of these statements might be true, they are practically impossible to prove scientifically. (CET-4 2003.12, Passage 1, Paragraph 1)

虽然其中有些话还是可信的，但是这些结论实际上不可能用科学的方法来验证。

30. And consumers would wait up to a decade to gain any benefits, because drilling could begin only after much bargaining over leases, environmental permits and regulatory review.(CET-4 2005.6, Passage 1, Paragraph 3)

而且，消费者还要等待10年之久才能有所获益，因为只有在租借、环保许可和调节评估等方面进行大量的谈判以后，石油钻探才可以开始。

31. According to a survey, which was based on the responses of over 188,000 students, today's traditional-age college freshmen are “more materialistic and less altruistic (利他主义的)” than at any time in the 17 years of the poll. (CET-4 2002.12, Passage 2, Paragraph 1)

根据一项基于对18万8千多名学生的调查，今天正常年龄的大学新生比17年以来任何时候的民间调查所反映的大学新生“更注重实用，更为利己”。

32. Open spaces are threatened by plans for housing estates and important habitats (栖息地) are endangered by highway construction . (CET-4 2005.6, Passage 4, Paragraph 2)

空旷的土地受到居民区开发计划的威胁，野生动物重要的栖息地正在受到高速公路建设的破坏

33. Obviously the justices did not shale their personal preferences, their mere likes and dislikes, they stated their considered judgment, painstakingly arrived at after thorough inquiry and deliberation. (CET-4 2003.9 Passage 4, Paragraph 3)

很清楚，法官们不是在陈述他们个人的好恶。他们在陈述一个经过深思熟虑的判决——一个经过艰苦的质询和审议才得出的结论。

34. A smoking airline pilot could fly adequately if no problems arose, but if something went wrong, smoking might damage his mental capacity. (CET-4 1998.6, Passage 1, Paragraph 6)

一个抽烟的飞行员，如果没有任何问题出现，他的飞行技术可能还不错，但是一旦有问题出现的时候，抽烟就会使他的大脑出现问题，不能很好地思考。

35. The graceless El Al Airlines, which is already at auction (拍卖)，has retrained its employees to emphasize service and is boasting about the results in an ad campaign with the slogan, “You can feel the change in the air.” (CET-4 2002.12, Passage 4, Paragraph 2)

原先服务恶劣的El Al 航空公司正在拍卖之中，也严格要求其员工重视服务，并在广告宣传标语中这样吹嘘其结果，“你在空气中都能感觉到变化”。

36. They described her as “very ill-informed” and a “loose cannon”。(CET-4 2004.6, Passage 4, Paragraph 3)

他们把她说成“孤陋寡闻”和“乱放炮”的人

37. Consequently, most of the world's fridges are to be found, not in the tropics where they might prove useful, but in the wealthy countries with mild temperatures where they are climatically almost unnecessary. (CET-4 1997.6, Passage 1, Paragraph 4)

结果是，在赤道附近最需要电冰箱的地方，没有电冰箱；而电冰箱主要存在于一些比较富有的国家，那些国家气候温和，根本就用不着电冰箱。

38. Among the report’s more outrageous findings --- a German fertilizer described itself as “ earthworm friendly” a brand of flour said it was “non-polluting” and a British toilet paper claimed to be “environmentally friendlier” （CET-4, 2005.6 Passage 3, paragraph 2）

在该研究报告几乎令人无法容忍的调查结果中：一种德国产化肥声称其“对蚯蚓无害”，一种面粉说自己是“无污染的”，而一款英国产出卫生纸上有“更加环保的”字样。

39. Then there is the general, all-covering apology, which avoids the necessity of identifying a specific act that was particularly hurtful or insulting, and which the person who is apologizing should promise never to do again. （CET-4, 2005.12 Passage 4, paragraph 4）

还有一种情况是笼统的、涵盖一切的道歉。这种道歉避免了认识一些特别使人伤心或者无礼的具体行为的必要性，并且道歉人应该保证以后不再犯。

40. In a 2001 study of 158 hospital nurses, those who faced considerable work demand but coped with the challenge were more likely to say they were in good health than those who felt they stress that you can manage may also boost immune(免疫的) function. （CET-4, 2005.12 Passage 3, paragraph 2）

在2001年进行的一项对158名护士的调查表明，那些面临的工作量虽大但应对了挑战的人要比那些认为他们不能完成工作的人更可能处于良好的健康状态，可以克服的压力也可以促进人的免疫功能。
